（空气呼啸）
(air whooshing)
（笑脸点击）
(smiley clicking)
（空气呼啸）
(air whooshing)
- 让我们看看如何预处理数据集以进行文本摘要。
- Let's see how to preprocess a dataset for summarization.
这是概括一份长文档的任务。
This is the task of, well, summarizing a long document.
该视频将重点介绍如何预处理你的数据集
This video will focus on how to preprocess your dataset
一旦你成功将其按照以下格式处理：
once you have managed to put it in the following format:
用一列表示长文件，
one column for the long documents,
和一列表示摘要。
and one for the summaries.
这是我们
Here is how we can achieve this
如何使用 XSUM 数据集上的 Datasets 库实现这一效果。
with the Datasets library on the XSUM dataset.
只要你设法让你的数据看起来像这样，
As long as you manage to have your data look like this,
你应该能够按照相同的步骤操作。
you should be able to follow the same steps.
这一次，我们的标签不是整数
For once, our labels are not integers
对应于某些类，但纯文本。
corresponding to some classes, but plain text.
因此，我们需要将它们标记化，就像我们的输入一样。
We will thus need to tokenize them, like our inputs.
虽然那里有一个小陷阱，
There is a small trap there though,
因为我们需要标记我们的目标
as we need to tokenize our targets
在 as_target_tokenizer 上下文管理器中。
inside the as_target_tokenizer context manager.
这是因为我们添加的特殊标记
This is because the special tokens we add
输入和目标可能略有不同，
might be slightly different for the inputs and the target,
所以 tokenizer 必须知道它正在处理哪个。
so the tokenizer has to know which one it is processing.
处理整个数据集非常容易
Processing the whole dataset is then super easy
与地图功能。
with the map function.
由于摘要通常要短得多
Since the summaries are usually much shorter
比文件，你绝对应该选择
than the documents, you should definitely pick
输入和目标的不同最大长度。
different maximum lengths for the inputs and targets.
你可以选择在此阶段填充到最大长度
You can choose to pad at this stage to that maximum length
通过设置 padding=max_length。
by setting padding=max_length.
在这里，我们将向你展示如何动态填充，
Here we'll show you how to pad dynamically,
因为它还需要一步。
as it requires one more step.
你的输入和目标都是句子
Your inputs and targets are all sentences
各种长度。
of various lengths.
我们将分别填充输入和目标
We'll pad the inputs and targets separately
作为输入和目标的最大长度
as the maximum lengths of the inputs and targets
是完全不同的。
are completely different.
然后，我们将输入填充到最大长度
Then, we pad the inputs to the maximum lengths
在输入之间，对于目标也是如此。
among the inputs, and same for the target.
我们用 pad token 填充输入，
We pad the input with the pad token,
以及索引为 -100 的目标
and the targets with the -100 index
确保不考虑它们
to make sure they are not taken into account
在损失计算中。
in the loss computation.
变形金刚库为我们提供
The Transformers library provide us
使用数据整理器自动完成这一切。
with a data collator to do this all automatically.
然后你可以将它与你的数据集一起传递给培训师，
You can then pass it to the Trainer with your datasets,
或者在使用 model.fit 之前在 to_tf_dataset 方法中使用它
or use it in the to_tf_dataset method before using model.fit
在你当前的模型上。
on your current model.
（空气呼啸）
(air whooshing)